Thank you Maria. Thank you for everything you said so kind and congratulations
to the
fellow inductees. I'm really humbled by your accomplishments and your
dedication. Congratulations. I have been raised and born in Cleveland and
have lived in Cleveland all my life. My grandparents came from Hungary, met and
married in Cleveland and were proud Americans. I have had a
good fortune of marrying a Hungarian who was born and raised in Hungary. He was
shot fighting for the freedom of his country in 1956. He
served five years in the US Army and settled in Cleveland. There is no more
loyal and proud American than Jim. My work with El Barrio began with the need
in the
Hispanic community. My background is in human resources within the company that
my husband and I founded in 1970. This led to my chairmanship of the El Barrio
program and jobs committee. I love to work and I have always loved my work. At
El Barrio I worked with people who had the same values and work
at this. When you are surrounded by people who have a passion for their
heritage it is contagious. The Cleveland Hungarian development panel has given
back to
Hungarians in the form of youth programs and scholarships. It is an all
volunteer organization that has given more than one million to Hungarian youth.
The
Hungarian cultural center of Northeastern Ohio and the Hungarian heritage
museum carry on the Hungarian tradition in their Hungarian village and also
their
museum. I have wonderful role models in the Hungarian cultural garden. We have
members who have dedicated a lifetime to the garden. A past inductee Ernie Meeha.
We have
members who have danced as children and took part in the garden dedication in
1938. Another past inductee Jenny Brown. We also have many young people who
work along with us
today such as the Raddick's who are here tonight. You don't need to be a first
generation or even speak the language of your ancestors to carry on their
heritage. Love of tradition comes from the heart. Music and arts are universal
in language and bring us all together. My work in the Hungarian cultural
garden is a labor of love. The garden is 78 years old, 78 years young and is in
the midst of a restoration project. The garden's legacy wall tells the story of
the
cultural arts of Hungarian. It is the first new installation in nearly 50 years.
We filled our garden with the music of Hungarian composers and musicians. Our
annual concert in the garden is free and open to all. Our ancestors in 1938
created this garden for the benefit of all Clevelanders. As we pass this
treasure to
a new generation we pay homage and thanks to our ancestors. In the cultural
garden we are surrounded by people who are passionate about their heritage.
There are
currently 29 active gardens in the federation and their number is growing. The
Cleveland Cultural Gardens is one of the best and most unique assets of
Cleveland.
As was mentioned earlier this is a special year for the Cultural Gardens as
they celebrate their 100th anniversary and continue their tradition of peace
through mutual
understanding. The cultural garden chain is a living example of cooperation
among the diverse ethnic communities of Cleveland and a tribute to the greater
Cleveland
area as an international city. As the gardens move into their second century we
will all celebrate with them. We will carry on the tradition of the past 100
years and
embrace the cultures of the second century of ethnic Clevelanders. Thank you.